<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <rss version="2.0">
      <channel>
        <title>LatAm Prompt News Digest</title>
        <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
        <description>A daily digest of curated Latin American news.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 08:32:19 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <managingEditor>LatAm Prompt News Feed</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>LatAm Prompt News Feed</webMaster>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      
    <item>
      <title>LatAm Prompt News Digest - August 20, 2025</title>
      <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-08-20</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 08:32:19 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>LatAm Prompt News Feed</author>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <h3><a href="https://www.politico.com/news/magazine/2025/08/19/donald-trump-panama-canal-mulino-00513603">‘I Don’t Think There’s a Government in Latin America That Has Given In More’</a> &mdash; Politico</h3>
      <p>Jared G. Mitovich is a journalist who uses data, public records and on-the-ground reporting to tell global stories about money, power and influence. He is an Overseas Press Club Foundation scholar and an incoming news associate at The Wall Street Journal. He graduated from the University of Pennsylvania. </p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/08/19/arts/rodrigo-moya-dead.html">Rodrigo Moya, Who Photographed a Changing Latin America, Dies at 91</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>He documented poverty and protest in the 1950s and ’60, and he created indelible images of Che Guevara and Gabriel García Márquez.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/08/20/world/americas/canada-mexico-tariffs-trump.html">Facing Trump’s Threats, Mexico and Canada Draw Closer. Will It Last?</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>Mexico and Canada have long viewed each other with indifference or even distrust. They’re now talking about teaming up.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/aug/20/bolivia-presidential-election-socialism">How towering dominance of Bolivia’s socialist party came tumbling down</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>In strongholds such as El Alto, support for the Mas party that once made Evo Morales Bolivia’s first Indigenous president has ebbed away – leaving it on the brink of extinction
Amid the almost monochrome landscape of bare-brick buildings in the high-altitude Bolivian city of El Alto, taller structures painted in garish colours and mirrored glass stand out, topped with giant statues of pop culture figures such as Batman and Iron Man.
The extravagant structures are known as “cholets”, a blend of chalet and cholo, the term used for people of Indigenous roots who moved to urban areas while retaining their cultural traits.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2025-08-20/chile-s-boric-wildfire-response-spotlights-presidential-failures">A Leftist Promise in Latin America Is Damaged by Boric's Failures</a> &mdash; Bloomberg</h3>
      <p>A Leftist Promise in Latin America Is Damaged by Boric's Failures</p>
      <hr/>
    ]]></description>
    </item>
</channel>
    </rss>