<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <rss version="2.0">
      <channel>
        <title>LatAm Prompt News Digest</title>
        <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
        <description>A daily digest of curated Latin American news.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 06:47:39 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <managingEditor>LatAm Prompt News Feed</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>LatAm Prompt News Feed</webMaster>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      
    <item>
      <title>LatAm Prompt News Digest - August 15, 2025</title>
      <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-08-15</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 06:47:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>LatAm Prompt News Feed</author>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/08/15/opinion/ecuador-galapagos-noboa.html">A Cloud Forest in Ecuador Is Crying for Help</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>Ecuador’s ecological progress is threatened by a series of reforms steamrolled by its young populist president, Daniel Noboa.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/features/2025-bolivia-central-bank-gold/">A Chaotic Gold Rush Is Helping Bolivia Prop Up Its Finances</a> &mdash; Bloomberg</h3>
      <p>A Chaotic Gold Rush Is Helping Bolivia Prop Up Its Finances</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/08/15/world/americas/bolivia-election-evo-morales.html">Evo Morales, Barred from Bolivia’s Election, Urges Null Votes</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>Despite being barred from running again for president and being sought for arrest, a towering figure of Bolivian politics is trying to rally supporters to cast null votes.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/aug/15/bolivia-presidential-election-right-wing">Bolivia election could see lurch to right as once-dominant party’s time runs out</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>The two leading presidential candidates are both rightwingers and the leftist party of former president Evo Morales faces potential extinction
In Plaza Murillo, the heart of Bolivia’s political capital, La Paz – and home to the presidential palace, parliament and the country’s main Catholic cathedral – time may be running out for a clock that runs backwards.
Installed atop of the congressional palace during the years of prosperity under former president Evo Morales, 65, the clock was conceived as a symbol of the “decolonial and anti-imperialist” worldview championed by the left.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/08/13/world/americas/ethan-guo-pilot-antarctica-chile.html">American Influencer Stuck Off Antarctica for 6 Weeks Says It’s ‘Isolating and Lonely’</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>Ethan Guo, a 20-year-old pilot and content creator, said that he has been effectively trapped at a Chilean base since June. The authorities had said he landed there without permission.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2025/08/14/a-martyr-in-the-making">A martyr in the making?</a> &mdash; The Economist</h3>
      <p>The killing of a senator may reshape Colombian politics</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2025/08/14/bolivias-crazy-kingdom-of-coca">Bolivia’s crazy kingdom of coca</a> &mdash; The Economist</h3>
      <p>Former leader Evo Morales is hiding out there</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2025/08/14/liberal-uruguay-and-the-right-to-die">Liberal Uruguay and the right to die</a> &mdash; The Economist</h3>
      <p>Could its approach spread across Latin America?</p>
      <hr/>
    ]]></description>
    </item>
</channel>
    </rss>