<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <rss version="2.0">
      <channel>
        <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed</title>
        <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
        <description>A daily digest of curated Latin American news.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 08:00:46 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <managingEditor>LatAm Prompt News Feed</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>LatAm Prompt News Feed</webMaster>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      
    <item>
      <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed - September 23, 2025</title>
      <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-09-23</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 08:00:46 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>LatAm Prompt News Feed</author>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <h3><a href="https://www.ft.com/content/e5e314d0-31cf-44e0-9167-63a787baac47">How Argentina’s Milei lost the markets and turned to Trump</a> &mdash; The Financial Times</h3>
      <p>Libertarian president’s tight grip on inflation cost him political capital and dollars</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.wsj.com/opinion/argentina-dollarization-peso-donald-trump-javier-milei-3bd3eeab">Opinion | How Trump Can Help Argentina’s Javier Milei</a> &mdash; The Wall Street Journal</h3>
      <p>The South American friend of the U.S. needs a stable currency, which probably requires dollarization.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.wsj.com/world/americas/argentina-is-losing-faith-in-mileis-free-market-revolution-9475ba42">Argentina Is Losing Faith in Milei’s Free-Market Revolution</a> &mdash; The Wall Street Journal</h3>
      <p>The Argentine leader faces shrinking public support as factories close and the economy falters before a pivotal midterm election.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2025/09/23/colombia-petro-interview-trump/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=wp_homepage">Colombian president: Trump’s boat strikes won’t stop narco traffickers</a> &mdash; The Washington Post</h3>
      <p>In an interview with The Washington Post, Colombia’s Gustavo Petro argued the Trump administration’s boat strikes are “only for television” and amount to “murder.”</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/sep/23/trinidadian-fishers-trump-caribbean-war-on-drugs">Trinidadian fishers fear getting caught in the crossfire amid Trump’s Caribbean ‘war on drugs’</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>Caribbean governments divided on US warship diplomacy as local fishers worry they could become collateral damage
At the Otaheite fishing depot on Trinidad’s west coast, fishers are busy gutting their morning catch on tables. Mounds of conch and small bait are stacked as wooden canoe-like fishing boats bob idly offshore.
On a day as clear as this, the mountains in Venezuela are visible on the horizon, so close is the island to the South American mainland. The Gulf of Paria, which separates the two countries, is deceptively calm. But many in the Caribbean fear a coming storm.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.ft.com/content/03cb69bf-2c55-497d-ad07-2ca40ec6bfcd">Does Trump want control of Venezuela’s oil?</a> &mdash; The Financial Times</h3>
      <p>Alongside concessions to Chevron, the administration appears to be using gunboat diplomacy to press Nicolás Maduro</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/sep/22/belem-residents-evicted-to-make-way-for-cop30-rentals">‘A heavy burden’: Belém residents evicted in rush for profits from Cop30 rentals</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>As the Brazilian city prepares to host 50,000 delegates, local people are being pushed from their homes
The two-bedroom apartment in Belém became Suelen Freitas’s home in 2020, when she moved her family to the same building as her elderly mother. On the edge of the Amazon rainforest, it was where her story played out for five years, from enduring the Covid pandemic, to watching her two children get into the university.
But in March everything changed. An eviction notice gave them and their neighbours 30 days to vacate their apartments. One by one, all 12 families were forced out. “It was very painful,” Freitas said.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    ]]></description>
    </item>
</channel>
    </rss>