<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <rss version="2.0">
      <channel>
        <title>LatAm Prompt News Digest</title>
        <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
        <description>A daily digest of curated Latin American news.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 09:51:06 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <managingEditor>LatAm Prompt News Feed</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>LatAm Prompt News Feed</webMaster>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      
    <item>
      <title>LatAm Prompt News Digest - August 13, 2025</title>
      <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-08-13</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 09:51:06 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>LatAm Prompt News Feed</author>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2025/aug/13/women-face-increased-violence-argentina-javier-milei">‘A whole spectrum of hatred’: women face increased violence in Milei’s Argentina as rights are eroded</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>In a country once lauded as a progressive bastion in Latin America, protections are being dismantled by a populist leader, and gender-based offences are on the rise
In the week before her murder, Fernanda Soledad Yramain lay awake at night listening as a motorbike circled the house where she was hiding. “She kept saying ‘it’s him’,” remembers Daniella Viscarra, Soledad’s sister-in-law with whom she had sought refuge in the Tucumán countryside. “She was scared all of the time.”
A month earlier, in September 2024, 29-year-old Soledad had ended a relationship with her boyfriend, Francisco Timoteo Saldaño. They had been together since she was 14 and he was 35, and shared three children. In the final year of their relationship, Saldaño had turned violent.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2gFBVV95cUxOc0ttYjNKejFDcnJqOVFTQmYzLTdwaGhaTWo4M1VpTjZsaDVNbFM1X3pUUFpYSHBBRzYyUXBmVVVCb2RacjMwLWdHcTlJX3hDTFk5TmhOOERZbGt0MWVIdktvWjhaY1h5NTdwN2lyUFFqYUsxWlRJazNQX0hYNmlZelFtTmROaFp2VWZGX0hNNWw3aFJMVTBiLTU4djc1SDBFZjdNT2wwSW0xY3JMNFhOQnRCZ21DS2ZjNG9FcmM3WDVJekhqcGFNdTN1aFdTNDVEb2t3UGlEVV9qdw?oc=5">Drugs and Gangs Are Menacing Latin America</a> &mdash; </h3>
      <p>Drugs and Gangs Are Menacing Latin America</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/aug/13/renato-freitas-curitiba-brazil">The ‘European capital of Brazil’ moves to expel Black politician from office – again</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>Experts say new removal cases against Renato Freitas show how Curitiba is ill-equipped to handle a defiant Black leader
In the more than 300-year history of the Brazilian city of Curitiba, no city councillor had ever been removed from office until 2022, when a promising young Black local politician was forced out.
Renato Freitas had been accused of “breaching parliamentary decorum” by leading an anti-racism protest that ended inside a Catholic church – ironically named Church of the Black Men and built by enslaved people in the 18th century.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    ]]></description>
    </item>
</channel>
    </rss>