<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <rss version="2.0">
      <channel>
        <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed</title>
        <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
        <description>A daily digest of curated Latin American news.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 07:02:02 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <managingEditor>LatAm Prompt News Feed</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>LatAm Prompt News Feed</webMaster>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      
    <item>
      <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed - October 07, 2025</title>
      <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-10-07</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 07:02:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>LatAm Prompt News Feed</author>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <h3><a href="https://www.wsj.com/opinion/time-for-milei-to-stop-passing-the-buck-1b2ae12e">Opinion | Time for Milei to Stop Passing the Buck</a> &mdash; The Wall Street Journal</h3>
      <p>A $20 billion swap line from the U.S. won’t cure what ails the Argentine peso.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-10-05/ars-usd-milei-defends-peso-while-billions-spent-outside-argentina">Argentines Blow Billions Shopping Abroad and Fan Currency Crisis</a> &mdash; Bloomberg</h3>
      <p>Argentines Blow Billions Shopping Abroad and Fan Currency Crisis</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.ft.com/content/80c5a710-a887-4107-9dcf-75cb8c6170c7">Argentines are losing patience with Milei’s sluggish economy</a> &mdash; The Financial Times</h3>
      <p>Libertarian leader has slashed inflation but austerity and strong peso have stalled activity</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2025/oct/06/argentina-el-chalten-los-glaciares-park-guardians-water-pollution-glacial-rivers">This Patagonian village has glacier-fed rivers and majestic scenery. The only problem? Sewage</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>El Chaltén is a paradise for hikers. But the seasonal influx of tourists stretches the sanitation infrastructure to breaking point – and even a legal victory has not provided a solution
When people in the Patagonian village of El Chaltén saw untreated waste flowing into waterways and found the sewage plant was faulty, they grew increasingly concerned about the health risks from pollution in two glacier-fed rivers, the Fitz Roy and Las Vueltas.
The incident in 2016 led Marie Anière Martínez, a conservationist with the Patagonian environmental organisation Boana, and Lorena Martínez, a Los Glaciares national park official, to form a group to investigate water contamination at the Unesco world heritage site.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/10/06/world/americas/mexico-canta-cartel-violence-music.html">Can Sweet Songs Prevail Over Bloody Ones? Mexico Is Giving It a Try.</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>On Sunday, three contestants were crowned winners of the inaugural, government-run “Mexico Sings” competition, meant to promote songs that aren’t about drug cartels or violence.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2025/oct/04/maya-heineken-brewery-yucatan-mexico-cenote-ring">Trouble brewing: Maya people in Yucatán fear new Heineken plant’s thirst for water</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>Indigenous groups in Mexico opposed to the planned brewery say families already have little access to water – and that their way of life is also under threat
On a summer evening in southern Mexico, a percussion group using water bottles as instruments leads a procession through Mérida, capital of Yucatán state. Children walking alongside elderly people are guided by members of Múuch’ Xíinbal, a Maya land rights organisation. The placards they carry declare: “Water is not for sale.” A heavy chant accompanies the march: “It’s not a drought – it’s plunder!”
At a rallying point in the city, protesters read from a manifesto and accuse the government of prioritising profit over water, health and land. They denounce a wave of mega-projects imposed without their consent, from industrial-scale pig farms to the controversial Maya Train tourist expansion. But they reserve their greatest anger for the Heineken brewery in Kanasín, near Mérida, which was announced in June.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/07/venezuela-on-edge-trump-regime-change-whispers">Venezuela on edge over Trump regime change whispers: ‘If it does happen we are ready’</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>Allies of President Nicolás Maduro vow to resist any military intervention but experts suspect Venezuela’s leaders were rattled by Trump’s decision to bomb Iran
The mayor of Caracas had come to one of her city’s busiest tube stations wearing a camouflage T-shirt declaring herself a card-carrying combatant – and with a message to match.
“They think they’re the owners of the world,” Carmen Meléndez complained of the Trump administration and its pressure campaign against Venezuela’s government. “But if they dare [to invade] we’ll be waiting for them here.”
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    ]]></description>
    </item>
</channel>
    </rss>