<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <rss version="2.0">
      <channel>
        <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed</title>
        <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
        <description>A daily digest of curated Latin American news.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:41:46 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <managingEditor>LatAm Prompt News Feed</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>LatAm Prompt News Feed</webMaster>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      
    <item>
      <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed - October 09, 2025</title>
      <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-10-09</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:41:46 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>LatAm Prompt News Feed</author>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <h3><a href="https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2025/10/08/the-argentine-peso-and-javier-milei-are-in-trouble">The Argentine peso, and Javier Milei, are in trouble</a> &mdash; The Economist</h3>
      <p>The president’s economic team has decamped to Washington, trying desperately to confirm American support</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2025/10/08/trump-venezuela-drug-boat-strikes-war/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=wp_homepage">Trump is turning the ‘war on drugs’ from metaphor into an actual war</a> &mdash; The Washington Post</h3>
      <p>Beyond the question of whether blowing up boats off Venezuela is legal, what’s the military objective?</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/10/09/world/americas/mexico-avocados-deforestation.html">Can Satellites Stop an Avocado Addiction From Killing Mexican Forests?</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>A new program using satellite imagery seeks to raise pressure on avocado growers by getting support from American buyers.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/09/brazil-bolsonaro-convicted-threat-coup">Brazil’s Bolsonaro was convicted but the military appetite for a coup lingers</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>Armed forces academies teach troops that military control would be better for the country, historians and experts say
Hours after supporters of the former president Jair Bolsonaro ransacked Brasília on 8 January 2023, three electricity pylons were brought down in different locations, between 1,000 miles and 1,800 miles away from Brazil’s capital.
In the following days, 21 more towers were toppled, all using the same method: bolts were removed from the base, and supporting steel cables were cut. The perpetrators knew exactly which power lines to sever to cause the most harm to the electricity supply.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    ]]></description>
    </item>
</channel>
    </rss>