<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <rss version="2.0">
      <channel>
        <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed</title>
        <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
        <description>A daily digest of curated Latin American news.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 07:45:02 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <managingEditor>LatAm Prompt News Feed</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>LatAm Prompt News Feed</webMaster>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      
    <item>
      <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed - August 25, 2025</title>
      <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-08-25</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 07:45:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>LatAm Prompt News Feed</author>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <h3><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2025-08-25/china-floods-latin-america-with-cheap-goods-through-temu-shein-mercadolibre">A Chinese E-Commerce Glut Is Meeting Resistance in Latin America</a> &mdash; Bloomberg</h3>
      <p>A Chinese E-Commerce Glut Is Meeting Resistance in Latin America</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2025/aug/25/we-get-nothing-residents-fight-back-as-mexico-builds-big-for-2026-world-cup">‘We get nothing’: residents fight back as Mexico builds big for 2026 World Cup</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>People living in the shadow of the country’s national Azteca Stadium in Mexico City say development plans will add to pressure on water sources and put green spaces at risk
Rubén Ramírez is no stranger to political battles. As a community leader in Santa Úrsula Coapa, a district in southern Mexico City, he’s become adept at taking on developers and bureaucrats to protect his neighbourhood over the past decade.
His latest fight may be his most ambitious yet: challenging the expansion of Mexico City’s national stadium ahead of the 2026 football World Cup, which he claims neglects the community’s ancient rights.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/08/23/world/americas/mexico-english-truckers-trump.html">Faced With Trump’s English Mandate, Mexico’s Truckers Report to Class</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>Companies, fearing penalties that could put them out of business, race to make sure their drivers have enough English to communicate with U.S. officials.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cvg4kd385e4o">A cut-off finger ended her comfortable family life. Now she's hiding from US officials</a> &mdash; BBC</h3>
      <p>Donald Trump declared some cartels to be terrorist organisations. So why are the victims of cartels in hiding?</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/aug/22/temporary-protected-status-tps-immigration-trump">Thousands face deportation to danger as Trump targets temporary protections</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>People with temporary protected status face possible deportation even though their home countries – including Afghanistan and Haiti – remain unsafe
Many thousands of immigrants living in the US who came from certain countries regarded as risky or dangerous are at the mercy of US judges and the Trump administration’s agenda to slash their work authorization and protection from deportation.
Since taking office, the Trump administration has announced the termination of temporary protected status (TPS) for citizens of seven of the 15 countries previously designated for shelter under this legal umbrella – with the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) controversially citing improved conditions in some of those places.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    ]]></description>
    </item>
</channel>
    </rss>