<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <rss version="2.0">
      <channel>
        <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed</title>
        <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
        <description>A daily digest of curated Latin American news.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 07:54:22 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <managingEditor>LatAm Prompt News Feed</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>LatAm Prompt News Feed</webMaster>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      
    <item>
      <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed - September 16, 2025</title>
      <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-09-16</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 07:54:22 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>LatAm Prompt News Feed</author>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/sep/15/colombia-violence-sex-slaves">Amid rising violence in Colombia, girls and women are being held as sex slaves: ‘No woman is safe’</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>The Catatumbo region, home to huge coca fields, has been ravaged by a fight for control between two armed groups
The rebels would come to the brothel every day, armed and masked. They would order the women to line up on their hands and knees, put their guns in their mouths, and rape them.
“It was ugly. A place filled with women and underage girls – all of us tricked and trapped,” recalled Valeria, 21, whose name has been changed to protect her identity. “The guerrillas came like they were there to kill.”
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2025-09-15/who-is-mercadolibre-s-meli-new-ceo-ariel-szarfsztejn-who-will-succeed-galperin">Meet the Man Who Wants to Run Latin America's Most Valuable Company Like a Startup</a> &mdash; Bloomberg</h3>
      <p>Meet the Man Who Wants to Run Latin America's Most Valuable Company Like a Startup</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2025/09/15/venezuela-drug-boat-military-strike-trump/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=wp_homepage">Trump brings the war on terror to the Caribbean</a> &mdash; The Washington Post</h3>
      <p>The military blows up another Venezuelan boat without congressional authorization.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2025/09/16/mexico-canta-narco-corrido-contest/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=wp_homepage">To fight the narcos, Mexico tries a new approach: A song contest</a> &mdash; The Washington Post</h3>
      <p>A Eurovision-style competition to counter narcocorridos, popular songs that romanticize the drug trade, draws viewers — and skeptics.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/sep/16/alexandre-padilha-brazil-minister-daughter-visa-revoked-trump">‘Diplomatic abuse’: Brazil minister on US revoking his 10-year-old daughter’s visa</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>Alexandre Padilha’s father fled dictatorship for the US – now the health chief’s family is a target of Trump’s bully tactics
When Alexandre Padilha’s father most needed help, the United States took him in.
It was 1971, the height of Brazil’s brutal two-decade dictatorship, and Anivaldo Padilha, a young Methodist activist, had been forced to flee his homeland after spending 11 months in one of São Paulo’s most notorious torture centres.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.ft.com/content/429d1a81-9ebe-4f58-9bef-2f73ce3dd094">Billionaire Carlos Slim’s growing presence in Mexico’s energy sector</a> &mdash; The Financial Times</h3>
      <p>The telecoms mogul has quietly increased his investments in the industry in the past decade</p>
      <hr/>
    ]]></description>
    </item>
</channel>
    </rss>