<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <rss version="2.0">
      <channel>
        <title>LatAm Prompt News Digest</title>
        <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
        <description>A daily digest of curated Latin American news.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 07:58:31 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <managingEditor>LatAm Prompt News Feed</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>LatAm Prompt News Feed</webMaster>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      
    <item>
      <title>LatAm Prompt News Digest - August 19, 2025</title>
      <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-08-19</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 07:58:31 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>LatAm Prompt News Feed</author>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <h3><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiuwFBVV95cUxQRklJa280NE9URnllZmtSZVZzbzkxbmJhc3BaakJwVFp1RFkxQUJfbEQ5RkI4TkdnX3Z0LVlGVmNOeFJJOXJRbGljSGRYV3B6MVV2QXdsLTVGZ2JJVTE1RW1TQlgtcVU3UTl0d21CV2tzT1hGTDB6bWtQWjhzM01PMWdDc05JQ2FjRGkzZ3NkSXhtQVFiTjZwRzJxanNPVG9HN1oxdGhwaU5yYlptVW5HWXZ1UzczWExucEdj?oc=5">Battle-Tested Cop Is Mexico's Hope to Tame Cartels and Placate Trump</a> &mdash; Bloomberg</h3>
      <p>Battle-Tested Cop Is Mexico's Hope to Tame Cartels and Placate Trump</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.ft.com/content/e6fa296e-fe44-4084-ad27-05808c62524c">Milei faces headless opposition in Argentina</a> &mdash; The Financial Times </h3>
      <p>Establishment parties struggle to regroup almost two years after political outsider’s victory</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/aug/18/mexico-welfare-policies-amlo">‘Historic’: how Mexico’s welfare policies helped 13.4 million people out of poverty</a> &mdash; The Guardian </h3>
      <p>Experts are enthusiastic about poverty reductions achieved under former Mexican president Andrés Manuel López Obrador
Toothless and frail, Gloria Palacios, 84, stooped as she set up her rickety sidewalk shop in Mexico City’s roughshod Doctores neighborhood. On sale: peanuts, cigarettes, chewing gum, chocolates and chips.
When asked how much she made in a day, Palacios’s disabled son Gustavo, who helps run the tiny store, simply laughed. “If we make 100 pesos ($5) it’s a lot,” he said. Happily, said Palacios, the family has a different lifeline.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2025/aug/18/scientists-claim-to-have-unlocked-secret-sauce-needed-for-fine-chocolate-cocoa">Scientists claim to have unlocked ‘secret sauce’ needed for fine chocolate</a> &mdash; The Guardian </h3>
      <p>Results of studying cocoa bean fermentation in Colombia could pave way to manipulate flavour, say researchers
Whether you enjoy an aromatic bar with notes of caramel or something less fancy, chocolate can have many tastes. Now researchers say they have shed fresh light on a key ingredient that could open the door to new flavours.
They claim to have unpicked how and why the bacteria and fungi involved in the fermentation of cocoa beans influence the flavour of chocolate.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/08/18/us/springfield-ohio-haitian-immigrants-trump.html">As Trump’s Policies Take Hold, Springfield, Ohio, Loses Its Haitian Work Force</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>Springfield faced a crisis after Donald Trump falsely claimed Haitians were eating pets. Now his policies are driving out workers like Wilford Rinvil, who left for Canada.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxNLWtuaU9rekdWWDhfOENaMWgzaFBwb293RzFMZ1ZjM3NXRFFCUkZpNzRETGxyaF9HVnF1NUtNMk53cEdRYTd2MUF1V2NtMHdybVdlczRoRGMwTXJVUktka25PM1d4UVFMRjBrNGZoaVB1MWlHZ1gyMHowd3dsZnJWZE5VX29yYU5SeGJaanJxVVU5T0k3X25xYXZfa3VJbGxkMVp6eEtPbldxbEdzYWlmMmFhdzU?oc=5">The Panama Canal Finds Itself at the Center of the World</a> &mdash; Bloomberg</h3>
      <p>The Panama Canal Finds Itself at the Center of the World</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.ft.com/content/dc6b17fc-ba19-47b7-8a54-a7216356bf47">The inexorable rise of Latin America’s drug cartels</a> &mdash; The Financial Times </h3>
      <p>With the global cocaine business booming as never before, organised crime groups are diversifying into a swath of other illicit activities</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/08/19/world/asia/vietnam-cuba-fundraising.html">Vietnamese Are Helping Cuba With 38-Cent Donations. A Lot of Them.</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>Cuba sent doctors and food to Vietnam during the war. Now ordinary Vietnamese are sending cash to struggling Cubans.</p>
      <hr/>
    ]]></description>
    </item>
</channel>
    </rss>