<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <rss version="2.0">
      <channel>
        <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed</title>
        <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
        <description>A daily digest of curated Latin American news.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 07:39:07 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <managingEditor>LatAm Prompt News Feed</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>LatAm Prompt News Feed</webMaster>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      
    <item>
      <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed - September 02, 2025</title>
      <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-09-02</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 07:39:07 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>LatAm Prompt News Feed</author>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/02/world/americas/jair-bolsonaro-brazil-coup-trial.html">How Jair Bolsonaro Tried, and Failed, to Stage a Coup in Brazil</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>Brazil’s former president, Jair Bolsonaro, stands trial on Tuesday, accused of plotting a coup after losing the 2022 elections. Evidence suggests this is how he tried to do it.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2025/09/01/brazil-bolsonaro-trial-coup-trump/">In Bolsonaro trial, Brazil confronts Trump — and its authoritarian past</a> &mdash; The Washington Post</h3>
      <p>Despite a long history of coups, no Brazilian general or politician has ever been tried in a courtroom for subverting the will of the people. Until this week.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/01/opinion/brazil-lula-trump-bolsonaro.html">Lula Faced Down Trump. Now Comes His Biggest Challenge.</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>For President Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva of Brazil, the stakes ahead of next year’s election could not be higher.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/02/science/brazil-meteorites.html">The Space Rock Stars of Brazil</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>An all-female research group, As Meteoriticas, scours the South American country’s interior aiming to preserve meteorites for scientific study and public display.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.wsj.com/opinion/donald-trump-venezuela-war-ships-nicolas-maduro-cartels-03a24134">Opinion | Trump’s Venezuelan War Games</a> &mdash; The Wall Street Journal</h3>
      <p>Is this U.S. warship deployment preparing for more than fighting drug cartels in the Caribbean?</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.ft.com/content/66251e3a-662e-4427-904d-2dc4304c36b5">Is Trump’s mission in Venezuela to fight drugs or to topple its leader?</a> &mdash; The Financial Times</h3>
      <p>US administration keeps Nicolás Maduro on edge with naval deployment but few see Marines coming ashore</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.ft.com/content/2971a0e7-a4b2-4f19-bdc9-732b0778320c">The Argentine junta, the crusading lawyer and the imposter</a> &mdash; The Financial Times</h3>
      <p>After decades spent helping survivors, lawyer Javier Garín thought he’d seen it all. Then came a victim who changed everything</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/08/30/world/americas/mexico-us-trump-sheinbaum.html">Mexico’s President Struggles to Escape Trump’s Growing Demands</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>After months of negotiation and concessions, President Claudia Sheinbaum of Mexico has found herself in a cycle of pressure from the White House.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/world-at-work/mexican-border-town-thousands-jobs-lost-due-trump-tariffs-2025-09-01/">In Mexican border town, thousands of jobs lost due to Trump tariffs</a> &mdash; Reuters</h3>
      <p>In Mexican border town, thousands of jobs lost due to Trump tariffs</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/01/world/americas/mexico-cartel-weapons.html">With Drones and I.E.D.s, Mexico’s Cartels Adopt Arms of Modern War</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>Under pressure from the government and each other, some of Mexico’s most powerful criminal groups are amassing homemade mortars, land mines, rocket-propelled grenades and bomber drones.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/sep/01/mexico-jaguar-numbers-rise-conservation-drive">‘We’re winning a battle’: Mexico’s jaguar numbers up 30% in conservation drive</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>Conservationists hope that in 15 years species will no longer be at risk of extinction in Mexico – but challenges remain
In 2010, Gerardo Ceballos and a group of other researchers set out to answer a burning question: how many jaguars were there in Mexico? They knew there weren’t many: hunting, loss of habitat, conflict with cattle ranchers and other issues had pushed the population to the brink of extinction.
Ceballos and his team from the National Alliance for Jaguar Conservation (ANCJ) thought there were maybe 1,000 jaguars across the country. They decided to carry out the country’s first census of the animal to find out exactly how many there were. They found 4,100.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2025/08/28/perus-cartoonish-presidential-front-runner">Peru’s cartoonish presidential front-runner</a> &mdash; The Economist</h3>
      <p>In Rafael López Aliaga, or “Porky”, many voters see a man of action</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.wsj.com/world/americas/howard-buffett-colombia-cocaine-industry-f84ccd37">Warren Buffett’s Son Battles Colombia’s Booming Cocaine Trade</a> &mdash; The Wall Street Journal</h3>
      <p>‘We’re trying to chip away at it,’ Howard Buffett says, describing the programs he is funding to coax drug farmers to switch to legal crops.</p>
      <hr/>
    ]]></description>
    </item>
</channel>
    </rss>