<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <rss version="2.0">
      <channel>
        <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed</title>
        <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
        <description>A daily digest of curated Latin American news.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 05:55:02 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <managingEditor>LatAm Prompt News Feed</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>LatAm Prompt News Feed</webMaster>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      
    <item>
      <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed - September 12, 2025</title>
      <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-09-12</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 05:55:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>LatAm Prompt News Feed</author>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2025/sep/11/colombian-coastal-erosion-uramba-bahia-malaga-national-natural-park">The Colombian coastal village reinventing itself as seas rise</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>Intense high tides have destroyed homes and businesses in Juanchaco and affected 3,000 families. But many in the Afro-Colombian community that live there are choosing to ‘stay in a different way’
Words and photographs by Mario Toro Quintero

Buenaventura is the most important port on Colombia’s Pacific coast, handling about 40% of the country’s foreign trade and acting as the gateway to the Uramba Bahía Málaga national natural park. Every year, tens of thousands of tourists arrive there, heading to the village of Juanchaco or the beaches of Ladrilleros and La Barra.
But the coast around Juanchaco, in the Valle del Cauca department, is experiencing accelerated erosion that has already left damaged streets, collapsed homes and a local economy exposed to the elements.
On the beach front in Juanchaco, damage caused by the rising tides has forced some people to evacuate their homes
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.wsj.com/world/americas/denials-and-defiance-shape-venezuelas-response-to-u-s-threats-on-drugs-abeb1078">Denials and Defiance Shape Venezuela’s Response to U.S. Threats on Drugs</a> &mdash; The Wall Street Journal</h3>
      <p>With U.S. warships in the Caribbean to stop Venezuelan cocaine shipments, the regime in Caracas claims it knows nothing about the trafficking of drugs.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2025-09-11/from-chile-to-mexico-a-geopolitical-reset-looms-in-latin-america">Latin America Is About to Transform Beyond Recognition</a> &mdash; Bloomberg</h3>
      <p>Latin America Is About to Transform Beyond Recognition</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/12/opinion/trump-bolsonaro-conviction-democracy.html">One Country Knew What to Do When Its President Tried to Steal an Election</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>Brazil just succeeded where we failed.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/12/world/americas/chile-astronomer-atacama-light-pollution.html">A Defender of Darkness in the Darkest Place on Earth</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>A Chilean astronomer has become dedicated to battling light pollution in the Atacama Desert and preserve what is considered the best place on Earth to study space.</p>
      <hr/>
    ]]></description>
    </item>
</channel>
    </rss>