<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <rss version="2.0">
      <channel>
        <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed</title>
        <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
        <description>A daily digest of curated Latin American news.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 06:47:03 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <managingEditor>LatAm Prompt News Feed</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>LatAm Prompt News Feed</webMaster>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      
    <item>
      <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed - September 29, 2025</title>
      <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-09-29</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 06:47:03 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>LatAm Prompt News Feed</author>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/26/world/americas/milei-argentina-economy.html">Argentina’s President Vowed to Fix Its Economy. Then Came a Crisis.</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>President Javier Milei slashed inflation and spending, but it wasn’t enough to stave off an economic crisis. President Trump has offered him a lifeline.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.wsj.com/opinion/the-cure-for-the-run-on-the-argentine-peso-ae82129c">Opinion | The Cure for the Run on the Argentine Peso</a> &mdash; The Wall Street Journal</h3>
      <p>Milei promised to dollarize and close the central bank. What is he waiting for?</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/sep/28/why-trump-is-backing-argentinas-thatcherite-economics">Why Trump is backing Argentina’s Thatcherite economics | Heather Stewart</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>While Javier Milei’s shock therapy to tame inflation has won support from Washington and the IMF, ordinary Argentinians seem less impressed
“We’re backing him 100%, we think he’s done a fantastic job. Like us, he inherited a mess.” Donald Trump gave his enthusiastic endorsement to Javier Milei’s radical economic experiment, when the pair met in New York last week.
The US has declared itself ready to offer more than rhetorical support to the chainsaw-wielding Argentine president in the coming days, as Buenos Aires stands on the brink of a fresh financial crisis.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/26/world/americas/argentina-women-murder-instagram.html">Brutal Murder of 3 Women, Broadcast On Instagram, Shocks Argentina</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>The live streamed torture and killing of three young women in Buenos Aires has stunned the country, setting off worries about the increasing presence of drug cartels.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/sep/27/galapagos-islands-sexual-violence">Galápagos Islands, wildlife haven, faces a sexual violence epidemic: ‘Protection is nonexistent’</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>While Ecuador’s islands are protected for its rich fauna, they are not a place of safety for many of its women and girls
El Mango viewpoint on Isla Isabela, the least populated island of the Galápagos archipelago, offers panoramic views of lush mangroves and crystalline shores. But this idyllic spot was also the setting for the darkest of crimes.
“My daughter was 15 when a man without scruples or feelings did this thing to her,” said Carmen Torres, sitting at the kitchen table in a small house on the outskirts of the island’s main village, her eyes cast downwards to the floor. “He knew what he was doing. But these are children, and they are so vulnerable to manipulation,” she said.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2025-09-26/us-military-shouldn-t-be-leading-drug-war-against-cartels">The War on Drugs Shouldn’t Be the Military’s Fight</a> &mdash; Bloomberg</h3>
      <p>The War on Drugs Shouldn’t Be the Military’s Fight</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/28/world/americas/fear-and-hope-in-venezuela-as-us-warships-lurk.html">Fear and Hope in Venezuela as U.S. Warships Lurk</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>On a visit to Venezuela, The Times found a nation bracing for potential U.S. military action.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.wsj.com/world/americas/trump-latin-america-migration-drug-trade-05dec866">Trump Is Reasserting U.S. Dominion Over Latin America</a> &mdash; The Wall Street Journal</h3>
      <p>A region the administration sees as the “U.S.’s backyard” is crucial to the president’s goals of reining in migration and stemming drug flows.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2025/10/06/a-cuban-exodus-faces-trumps-america">Have Cubans Fled One Authoritarian State for Another?</a> &mdash; The New Yorker</h3>
      <p>In the past few years, as many as two million people have escaped the island’s repressive regime and collapsing economy. Those who’ve made it to the U.S. face a new reckoning.</p>
      <hr/>
    ]]></description>
    </item>
</channel>
    </rss>