<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <rss version="2.0">
      <channel>
        <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed</title>
        <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
        <description>A daily digest of curated Latin American news.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 07:42:43 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <managingEditor>LatAm Prompt News Feed</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>LatAm Prompt News Feed</webMaster>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      
    <item>
      <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed - September 05, 2025</title>
      <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-09-05</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 07:42:43 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>LatAm Prompt News Feed</author>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <h3><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2025/09/04/ai-china-latin-america-competition/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=wp_homepage">How to counter China’s AI push in Latin America</a> &mdash; </h3>
      <p>U.S. must offer the region a democratic alternative before Beijing’s technology becomes entrenched.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/sep/04/fentanyl-guns-us-mexico-border-arizona-california">New ‘golden triangle’ of fentanyl and guns spans US-Mexico border</a> &mdash; </h3>
      <p>Report links Arizona-Sonora smuggling to rising homicide and overdose deaths in both countries
A new “golden triangle” of fentanyl and gun trafficking between Mexico and the US ties together the homicide and overdose crises of the two countries, according to a a new study.
The triangle spans Baja, California, Sinaloa and Sonora – the three states where almost all fentanyl seizures in Mexico take place – and connects to Arizona through a quieter part of the US-Mexico border that has become a hotspot for trafficking in both directions.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/04/opinion/trump-cartel-boat-destroyed-venezuela-drugs.html">America’s War on Terror Comes to the Caribbean</a> &mdash; </h3>
      <p>The Trump administration seems to be betting that Americans are so inured to the war on terrorism that they’ll be indifferent to extrajudicial executions.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/sep/05/jair-bolsonaro-trial">Anatomy of a coup plot: why Jair Bolsonaro is on trial</a> &mdash; </h3>
      <p>The former Brazilian president and seven of his closest allies are awaiting judgment – and Bolsonaro’s conviction is considered highly likely
Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva was days away from taking office for his third term as the Brazilian president when soldiers from a special operations unit allegedly discussed the best way to kill him – possibly through poisoning or administering drugs that would trigger “organ failure”.
Investigators would later conclude that the supposed plan to assassinate the president-elect, his vice-president and a supreme court justice was one of many strands of a wider plot designed to keep the far-right leader Jair Bolsonaro in power.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.ft.com/content/ec0c835b-cfb3-4726-8f6d-252644df3a7b">A $125bn scheme to save the world’s rainforests</a> &mdash; </h3>
      <p>Brazil’s flagship initiative for COP30 is ambitious and innovative — but will face risks</p>
      <hr/>
    ]]></description>
    </item>
</channel>
    </rss>