<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <rss version="2.0">
      <channel>
        <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed</title>
        <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
        <description>A daily digest of curated Latin American news.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:02:57 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <managingEditor>LatAm Prompt News Feed</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>LatAm Prompt News Feed</webMaster>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      
    <item>
      <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed - September 30, 2025</title>
      <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-09-30</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 08:02:57 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>LatAm Prompt News Feed</author>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2025/sep/29/agriculture-deforestation-farming-soya-cultivation-eating-brazil-amazon">How the world’s taste for soya is eating Brazil’s Amazon</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>Cultivation of the crop has made a few wealthy but at a huge cost to untouched forest as it spreads across vast areas of former wilderness
Photographs by Avener Prado

In 2012, José Pereira do Nascimento lost his home when the Santo Antônio hydroelectric station in Porto Velho, in Brazil’s north-west Amazon basin, opened its floodgates. The 3,568MW plant, built to provide power for 45 million people, released a muddy torrent that flooded his neighbourhood, forcing 120 families to evacuate.
“The river has gone out of control. We used to know when it would flood and when it would dry up. Now nobody knows any more,” says Nascimento, a rancher. “What men call progress has killed our history.”
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/29/world/americas/brazil-digital-payments.html">Brazil’s Homegrown Payment System Is Target of Trump Administration</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>Brazil’s fast and free homegrown digital payment system, PIX, has become wildly popular. The Trump administration says it unfairly undercuts U.S. companies.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/sep/30/rio-wild-animals-gun-crime-victims">‘Not even animals escape the extreme barbarity’: wildlife caught in Rio’s rampant gun crime</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>From capuchin monkeys to mantled hawks – Instituto Vida Livre has treated a myriad of shot animals in a city blighted by gun crime
Maria was taking an afternoon stroll through one of Rio’s most desirable neighbourhoods when her life was turned on its head. When she was carried into a nearby clinic, unable to move her legs, doctors suspected she had been electrocuted or mauled by a dog.
The X-ray machine revealed a more sinister diagnosis: Maria had been shot, the bullet embedding itself in her spinal cord and leaving her paralysed from the abdomen down.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.ft.com/content/5f4bb8d6-e93c-4bf0-b0ae-f459255eb8c7">Other people’s money, and the problem with Mileism</a> &mdash; The Financial Times</h3>
      <p>The US Treasury needs to get Argentina on a better policy path before it blows through the Exchange Stabilization Fund</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2025-09-30/trump-deportations-why-remittances-to-latin-america-are-increasing">Trump’s Deportations Are Driving a Remittance Boom in Latin America</a> &mdash; Bloomberg</h3>
      <p>Trump’s Deportations Are Driving a Remittance Boom in Latin America</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/29/us/politics/maduro-venezuela-trump-rubio.html">Top Trump Aides Push for Ousting Maduro, Venezuela’s Leader</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>An opposition movement whose figures have met with U.S. officials says it is communicating with Washington on plans to dismantle Nicolás Maduro’s “criminal structure.”</p>
      <hr/>
    ]]></description>
    </item>
</channel>
    </rss>