<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <rss version="2.0">
      <channel>
        <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed</title>
        <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
        <description>A daily digest of curated Latin American news.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 07:30:35 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <managingEditor>LatAm Prompt News Feed</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>LatAm Prompt News Feed</webMaster>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      
    <item>
      <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed - September 17, 2025</title>
      <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-09-17</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 07:30:35 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>LatAm Prompt News Feed</author>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <h3><a href="https://www.ft.com/content/572f596a-fac3-4dbf-aade-8c46da20c8ab">Brazil’s rightwing succession: the hunt for a new Bolsonaro</a> &mdash; The Financial Times</h3>
      <p>São Paulo governor and family members among potential heirs to hard-right populist facing jail term</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2025/sep/17/guyana-oil-reserves-poverty-venezuela-chevron-exxon">Guyana found huge oil reserves 10 years ago, so why are most people still poor?</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>With a ‘one-sided’ deal handing vast profits to the world’s top oil firms, many Guyanese ask when the energy bonanza will benefit them
On 18 July, the International Chamber of Commerce approved the attempt by the US energy multinational Chevron to replace Hess Oil as a stakeholder in one of the world’s largest offshore oilfields, Guyana’s Stabroek, as part of its $55bn (£41bn) acquisition of the smaller company.
Yet, as Chevron executives celebrated joining Exxon and China National Offshore Oil Corporation (CNOOC) as in producing Guyana’s daily oil output of 650,000 barrels, the response from the Guyanese government, opposition leaders and environmentalists was muted.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/immigration/2025/09/17/trump-immigration-family-separations-children/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=wp_homepage">Trump’s mass deportations bring a new wave of family separations</a> &mdash; The Washington Post</h3>
      <p>Officers have referred more than 400 children to shelters run by the Office of Refugee Resettlement, according to two people who have reviewed internal records on the actions.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.wsj.com/world/americas/mexico-drugs-cartel-oseguera-trump-586f0cec">America Loves Cocaine Again—Mexico’s New Drug King Cashes In</a> &mdash; The Wall Street Journal</h3>
      <p>The Trump administration’s war on fentanyl created an opening for ‘El Señor Mencho’ to smuggle cocaine into the U.S. by the ton.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/sep/17/missing-land-defender-deadly-toll-land-conflict-indigenous-people">‘We’re still in the dark’: a missing land defender and the deadly toll of land conflict on Indigenous people</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>Julia Chuñil is one of 146 land defenders who were killed or went missing last year, a third of them from Indigenous communities
One day last November, Julia Chuñil called for her dog, Cholito, and they set off into the woods around her home to search for lost livestock. The animals returned but Chuñil, who was 72 at the time, and Cholito did not.
More than 100 people joined her family in a search lasting weeks in the steep, wet and densely overgrown terrain of Chile’s ancient Valdivian forest. After a month, they even kept an eye on vultures for any grim signs. But they found no trace of Chuñil.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2025-09-16/crime-in-peru-extortion-and-murder-rise-near-chancay-megaport">Extortion Gangs Are Circling Peru’s Ambitious $1.3 Billion Megaport</a> &mdash; Bloomberg</h3>
      <p>Extortion Gangs Are Circling Peru’s Ambitious $1.3 Billion Megaport</p>
      <hr/>
    ]]></description>
    </item>
</channel>
    </rss>