<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <rss version="2.0">
      <channel>
        <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed</title>
        <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
        <description>A daily digest of curated Latin American news.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 06:52:59 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <managingEditor>LatAm Prompt News Feed</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>LatAm Prompt News Feed</webMaster>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      
    <item>
      <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed - September 22, 2025</title>
      <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-09-22</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 06:52:59 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>LatAm Prompt News Feed</author>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <h3><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/climate-solutions/2025/09/19/uruguay-renewable-energy-climate-breakthrough/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=wp_homepage">He got an entire country running on clean energy. Can he do it again?</a> &mdash; The Washington Post</h3>
      <p>Ramón Méndez Galain helped Uruguay decarbonize its grid in just five years, with 98 percent of its energy coming from renewable sources.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.wsj.com/opinion/donald-trump-venezuela-cartels-nicolas-maduro-d374cef7">Opinion | What Does Trump Want in Venezuela?</a> &mdash; The Wall Street Journal</h3>
      <p>Deposing Maduro is in the U.S. interest, and America should help if Venezuelans lead..</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2025/sep/22/illness-animal-deaths-water-shortages-chile-polluted-sacrifice-zones-anglo-american-mining">Illness, animal deaths and water shortages: life inside Chile’s polluted ‘sacrifice zones’</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>Allegations of environmental breaches dog Anglo American’s mining operations. Now the company has been given the go-ahead for plans that communities say risk disaster
Photographs by Nicole Kramm

Patricia Silva lays out an array of medicines and doctors’ letters on her kitchen table. She lives a few kilometres from a copper foundry operated by the British-headquartered mining company Anglo American in Catemu, a town in central Chile. Every morning and evening, she says, the air is filled with a faint blue smoke.
“It irritates your throat and makes you cough,” Silva says, remembering a day when her son Cristián, then three years old, began to have convulsions. “His face turned purple and he couldn’t breathe. He still has a red mark on his face from that episode.”
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/sep/20/insane-journeys-inside-the-narco-subs-that-cross-oceans-carrying-hundreds-of-millions-of-pounds-of-cocaine">‘Insane journeys’: inside the narco-subs that cross oceans carrying hundreds of millions of pounds of cocaine</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>Poorly paid crews risk their lives on voyages in ‘propeller-driven coffins’ to smuggle drugs from Brazil to Europe
What was going through the mariners’ minds, embarking on a voyage they must have feared they would not survive? How did they bid farewell to their loved ones before setting off? What had driven them to accept such a mission? The answers to those questions, like the identities of the sailors, remain a mystery to Brazilian police.
What investigators are certain of is the purpose of the vessel: a dungeon-like “narco-submarine” that they say was days away from starting a hellish three-week odyssey across the Atlantic carrying hundreds of millions of pounds-worth of cocaine to Europe.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/20/world/americas/nicaragua-ortega-arrests.html">They Helped Oust a Dictator. Now the New Regime Is Coming for Them.</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>President Daniel Ortega of Nicaragua and his wife, who is co-president, have been arresting longtime loyalists, in an apparent quest to ensure no one outside the family rises to power.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/21/world/americas/mexico-politicians-fashion.html">The High School Teacher Leading Mexico’s ‘Fashion Police’</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>A teacher and journalist has gained a large following for highlighting the apparent luxury items worn by politicians. It has also earned him high-profile detractors.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2025-09-19/pedernales-cabo-rojo-the-new-caribbean-vacation-spot-in-dominican-republic">Pristine Beaches and Cruises: A New Caribbean Vacation Spot Emerges</a> &mdash; Bloomberg</h3>
      <p>Pristine Beaches and Cruises: A New Caribbean Vacation Spot Emerges</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.wsj.com/opinion/are-mexican-politicians-running-cartels-5437c36e">Opinion | Are Mexican Politicians Running Cartels?</a> &mdash; The Wall Street Journal</h3>
      <p>A former government official is arrested on charges of operating a criminal network.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2025/09/21/is-colombia-at-the-gates-of-hell">Is Colombia at the “gates of hell”?</a> &mdash; The Economist</h3>
      <p>Opposing candidates in next year’s presidential election hold wildly divergent views of their country</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2025/sep/19/trinidad-tobago-economy-oil-gas-fossil-fuels-climate-green-transition">‘A defining moment’: Trinidad and Tobago at a crossroads as oil runs out</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>Fossil fuels made the nation prosperous but as reserves dwindle, do they drill deeper, even as the Caribbean feels the heat of the climate crisis, or shift to a greener economy?

In 1930, Trinidad and Tobago produced more than 40% of the British empire’s oil. By the 1970s, the newly independent republic was producing 278,000 barrels of crude oil a day. For a country of just 1 million people, after the collapse of its sugar and cocoa industries, oil proved to be transformative.
Today, with a population of 1.5 million and oil production down to less than 54,000 barrels a day, Trinidad and Tobago is at a crossroads. The country’s only petroleum refinery closed in 2018 due to mismanagement and declining production by the state-owned Petrotrin company. A recent analysis noted that the energy revenues plummeted 48.4% to $14.7bn (£10.9bn) in the last fiscal year, while non-energy revenues grew by 26% to $32.7bn.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    ]]></description>
    </item>
</channel>
    </rss>