<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <rss version="2.0">
      <channel>
        <title>LatAm Prompt News Digest</title>
        <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
        <description>A daily digest of curated Latin American news.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 07:54:33 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <managingEditor>LatAm Prompt News Feed</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>LatAm Prompt News Feed</webMaster>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      
    <item>
      <title>LatAm Prompt News Digest - August 21, 2025</title>
      <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-08-21</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 07:54:33 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>LatAm Prompt News Feed</author>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <h3><a href="https://www.wsj.com/world/americas/a-gold-trading-dynasty-vies-for-power-in-oil-rich-guyana-c1735809">A Gold-Trading Dynasty Vies for Power in Oil-Rich Guyana</a> &mdash; The Wall Street Journal</h3>
      <p>Azruddin Mohamed, a flamboyant scion sanctioned by the U.S., aims to become president in next month’s elections.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2025/08/21/mexico-immigrants-money-remittances-trump/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=wp_homepage">Migrants are sending less money to Mexico. Trump is only part of why.</a> &mdash; The Washington Post</h3>
      <p>Falling remittances are leaving a mark on Mexico. They could drive more people to the border.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/08/21/opinion/trump-cartel-mexico-fentanyl.html">The Folly of Trump’s Cartel-Bombing Fantasy</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>A U.S. strike on cartels in Mexico won’t fix the deep problems that allow organized crime to flourish.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/aug/21/brazil-authorities-suspend-key-amazon-rainforest-protection-measure">Brazil authorities suspend key Amazon rainforest protection measure</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>Suspension of soy moratorium could open up area of rainforest the size of Portugal to destruction
One of the key agreements for Amazon rainforest protection – the soy moratorium – has been suspended by Brazilian authorities, potentially opening up an area the size of Portugal to destruction by farmers.
Coming less than three months before Brazil hosts the Cop30 climate summit in Belém, the news has shocked conservation groups, who say it is now more important than ever that consumers, supermarkets and traders stand up against Brazilian agribusiness groups that are using their growing political power to reverse past environmental gains.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/08/21/world/americas/brazil-us-rare-earth-minerals-tariffs.html">Brazil-U. S. Talks on Mining Rare Earth Minerals Are Complicated by Trump’s Tariffs</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>Tensions between President Trump and Brazil’s leader could derail a promising alliance to unlock the world’s second largest reserve of the minerals.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2025/08/21/bolivia-president-election-center-right/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=wp_homepage">Bolivia’s promising turn to the right</a> &mdash; The Washington Post</h3>
      <p>Voters have apparently had enough of Evo Morales’s enviro-socialist governing model.</p>
      <hr/>
    ]]></description>
    </item>
</channel>
    </rss>