<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <rss version="2.0">
      <channel>
        <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed</title>
        <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
        <description>A daily digest of curated Latin American news.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 08:17:40 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <managingEditor>LatAm Prompt News Feed</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>LatAm Prompt News Feed</webMaster>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      
    <item>
      <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed - September 18, 2025</title>
      <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-09-18</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 08:17:40 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>LatAm Prompt News Feed</author>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/2025/sep/17/chinas-emerging-superpower-status-relies-on-africa-and-the-caribbean-but-is-all-as-it-seems">China is eyeing superpower status via Africa and the Caribbean. But are they partners or pawns?</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>Many are questioning whether China’s growing footprint in the Black diaspora is mutually beneficial
Don’t get The Long Wave delivered to your inbox? Sign up here

At a high-profile global summit held by China this month, there were strong statements directed at the west’s “bullying” as well as renewed calls to stabilise “global governance”. The meeting was the clearest indication yet that China is vying to become a world superpower, aiming to marshal an anti-western bloc. But the foundations of that position partly lie in Africa and the Caribbean, where China has been building relationships for decades.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.ft.com/content/671577a8-ab27-4ebe-b192-5e8e52b7890e">A Brazilian court decision that bolsters democracy</a> &mdash; The Financial Times</h3>
      <p>Bolsonaro’s conviction makes history by holding a coup plotter to account</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.newyorker.com/podcast/political-scene/how-bad-is-it-political-violence-in-the-us-and-what-we-can-learn-from-brazil">How Bad Is It?: Political Violence in the U.S., and What We Can Learn from Brazil</a> &mdash; The New Yorker</h3>
      <p>Brazil’s reckoning with authoritarianism may hold lessons for a U.S. system under strain.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.ft.com/content/315f7420-104a-40f5-ad2e-12520cb095ad">The great Chilean baby bust</a> &mdash; The Financial Times</h3>
      <p>Increased social mobility and high living costs contribute to 42% drop in fertility rate in past decade</p>
      <hr/>
    ]]></description>
    </item>
</channel>
    </rss>