<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <rss version="2.0">
      <channel>
        <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed</title>
        <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
        <description>A daily digest of curated Latin American news.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 06:47:36 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <managingEditor>LatAm Prompt News Feed</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>LatAm Prompt News Feed</webMaster>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      
    <item>
      <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed - August 28, 2025</title>
      <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-08-28</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 06:47:36 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>LatAm Prompt News Feed</author>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <h3><a href="https://www.ft.com/content/50db68c8-59d2-4a2a-b2c3-7c8c88237763">US naval build-up near Venezuela stokes tensions in Latin America</a> &mdash; The Financial Times</h3>
      <p>Deployment of warships and thousands of sailors prompts Nicolás Maduro to call up militia</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2025/08/27/el-mayo-mexico-sheinbaum-corruption/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=wp_homepage">El Mayo’s guilty plea could shake Mexico to its core</a> &mdash; The Washington Post</h3>
      <p>The Sinaloa cartel leader’s revelations will put pressure on Claudia Sheinbaum to act.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/aug/27/javier-milei-sister-argentina-alleged-kickbacks">Javier Milei reels from ‘scandal’ tying powerful sister to alleged kickbacks</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>Leaked audio links Karina Milei, sister of Argentina’s president, to alleged kickbacks in drug contracts for the disabled
Argentina’s president Javier Milei is facing his administration’s worst alleged corruption scandal – involving none other than his hugely influential sister, Karina – less than two months before key legislative elections.
For more than a week, news in the country has been dominated by audio recordings in which a former government official is heard discussing the alleged payment of bribes linked to the purchase of medicines for people with disabilities.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/08/27/world/americas/el-salvador-schools-military.html">El Salvador Enacts Military-Style Rules on Haircuts and More in Schools</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>President Nayib Bukele says that his new education minister, a military officer, will restore discipline to schools where gangs once recruited. A school workers’ union called the appointment “absurd.”</p>
      <hr/>
    ]]></description>
    </item>
</channel>
    </rss>