<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <rss version="2.0">
      <channel>
        <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed</title>
        <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
        <description>A daily digest of curated Latin American news.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 06:58:37 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <managingEditor>LatAm Prompt News Feed</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>LatAm Prompt News Feed</webMaster>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      
    <item>
      <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed - September 08, 2025</title>
      <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-09-08</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 06:58:37 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>LatAm Prompt News Feed</author>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/06/world/americas/javier-milei-karina-argentina-leaked-audio.html">Karina Milei, Argentina’s Mysterious First Sister, Captivates Nation After Audio Leaks</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>Karina Milei has become a lightning rod for corruption accusations even as her power and the loyalty of her brother, President Javier Milei, remain unwavering.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.wsj.com/opinion/mileis-experiment-may-be-losing-steam-01c46925">Opinion | Milei’s Experiment May Be Losing Steam</a> &mdash; The Wall Street Journal</h3>
      <p>Argentina’s Peronists won’t stop fighting the outsider president’s pro-market agenda.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2025/09/04/what-is-missing-from-a-plan-to-tackle-haitis-gangs">What is missing from a plan to tackle Haiti’s gangs</a> &mdash; The Economist</h3>
      <p>Boots on the ground can only solve some of the country’s ills</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2025/09/07/haiti-gangs-security-united-nations/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=wp_homepage">A new U.S. plan offers hope for Haiti</a> &mdash; The Washington Post </h3>
      <p>Fresh attention on our Caribbean backyard could prevent the country from becoming a narco-state.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2025/sep/07/they-grabbed-us-like-dogs-deportation-quotas-tear-haitian-migrants-lives-apart">‘They grabbed us like dogs’: deportation quotas tear Haitian migrants’ lives apart</a> &mdash; The Guardian </h3>
      <p>In the Dominican Republic, batey slums housing sugarcane workers from Haiti fear immigration raids and extortion
On the yellow bus rumbling through the Dominican Republic’s sugarcane fields back to the settlement, Sainristil sat among the jolting bodies of other Haitian workers in ripped orange shirts. These journeys are routine – always the same grumbling stomachs in anticipation of dinner, the same chatter among men who share a job, a home and a homeland.
But that evening, as the workers’ bus pulled into the cul-de-sac of communal housing, it came to a halt before two white buses marked with the words “Migration control”.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirAFBVV95cUxPRWR3WUxEWUp3UTduUFBMemVnOWx6WV9BaVptQXVYb3hDaGdwZ1lvRGJCdFhmTnFZb2FTYVZZREZnUHFKRVcxdzZtTC1uN1ZyaUhaaUdBX01ndHdzc0NzeVVpMlEzTFZhSGg4RnFOUGlLYVA2WGZWTmNabkxVVFE1R2p2aUxWajJIMVRUeHpLR0szaklSSE1jSVZPTWR5TC15eFpwcGxPTlpFUWVf?oc=5">Mexico Sees a Future in Shale Gas. Just Don’t Call it Fracking.</a> &mdash; Bloomberg</h3>
      <p>Mexico Sees a Future in Shale Gas. Just Don’t Call it Fracking.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.economist.com/the-americas/2025/09/04/luring-partners-and-yet-more-debt-mexicos-energy-plan">Luring partners and yet more debt: Mexico’s energy plan</a> &mdash; The Economist</h3>
      <p>The state oil firm needs a more radical treatment</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/08/dining/mexico-city-food-restaurants.html">What Happened to Mexico City’s Food Scene? Americans.</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>As restaurants change to reflect new tastes, local reactions have ranged from fascination to fury.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/08/opinion/colombia-violence-drugs-petro.html">A New War Is Emerging in Colombia</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>Colombia’s return to conflict is a lesson in how hard it is to sustain progress toward peace.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2025/09/15/enemies-of-the-state">How ICE Turned Venezuelan Migrants Into Enemies of the State</a> &mdash; The New Yorker</h3>
      <p>How the Trump Administration declared war on Venezuelan migrants in the U.S.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.ft.com/content/40db955e-f229-45bf-8987-49d22b321aca">The trial that split Brazil</a> &mdash; The Financial Times </h3>
      <p>Ex-president Jair Bolsonaro awaits verdict on coup-plotting charges as divisions deepen and a crisis with US looms</p>
      <hr/>
    ]]></description>
    </item>
</channel>
    </rss>