<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <rss version="2.0">
      <channel>
        <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed</title>
        <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
        <description>A daily digest of curated Latin American news.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 08:18:02 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <managingEditor>LatAm Prompt News Feed</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>LatAm Prompt News Feed</webMaster>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      
    <item>
      <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed - October 03, 2025</title>
      <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-10-03</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 08:18:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>LatAm Prompt News Feed</author>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <h3><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2025-10-02/trump-immigration-curbs-diaspora-fatigue-push-venezuelans-home">Why Some Venezuelans Are Turning Back Home After Years Abroad</a> &mdash; Bloomberg</h3>
      <p>Why Some Venezuelans Are Turning Back Home After Years Abroad</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/immigration/2025/10/03/asylum-venezuelan-singer-ice-detention/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=wp_homepage">A Venezuelan singer won asylum. ICE detained him for two more months.</a> &mdash; The Washington Post</h3>
      <p>The singer known online as Davicito59 won his asylum case in July. Still, ICE kept him in custody for two more months — a holdup several experts called unlawful.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/oct/02/lifting-black-cloud-smog-bound-city-cut-dangerous-levels-air-pollution">Lifting the ‘constant black cloud’: how a smog-bound city cut dangerous levels of air pollution</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>A 30-year effort driven by long-term policies is finally paying off in Santiago in Chile – but the challenge is far from over
In Santiago, this winter was different. The mountains surrounding the city – the same ones that usually trap smog and turn it into a “pressure cooker” – were visible more days than usual.
For nearly 30 years Chile’s capital has been experimenting in how to reduce air pollution; in the last few years the work has at last begun paying dividends and 2025 was the third best year in terms of fewest hours of critical pollution episodes since the first atmospheric prevention and decontamination plan in 1997. Over the last decade, hours of exposure to high levels of pollution fell by 66%, which, according to the environment minister, Maisa Rojas, means the 7.5 million residents of the metropolitan region “are breathing cleaner air”.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/chilean-wines-boom-brazil-tariffs-dampen-us-demand-2025-10-02/">Chilean wines boom in Brazil as tariffs dampen US demand</a> &mdash; Reuters</h3>
      <p>Chilean wines boom in Brazil as tariffs dampen US demand</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2025/10/02/haiti-un-security-council-gang-suppression-force/">New U.N. force for Haiti offers hope, if the U.S. stays involved</a> &mdash; The Washington Post</h3>
      <p>Gangs control 90 percent of the capital in Port-au-Prince, but perhaps not for long.</p>
      <hr/>
    ]]></description>
    </item>
</channel>
    </rss>