<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <rss version="2.0">
      <channel>
        <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed</title>
        <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
        <description>A daily digest of curated Latin American news.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 05:34:25 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <managingEditor>LatAm Prompt News Feed</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>LatAm Prompt News Feed</webMaster>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      
    <item>
      <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed - September 15, 2025</title>
      <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-09-15</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 05:34:25 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>LatAm Prompt News Feed</author>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/14/opinion/lula-da-silva-brazil-trump-bolsonaro.html">Lula: Brazilian Democracy and Sovereignty Are Non-Negotiable</a> &mdash; The New York Times </h3>
      <p>The president of Brazil calls U.S. tariffs on his country “not only misguided but also illogical” and defends former President Jair Bolsonaro’s conviction.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.wsj.com/opinion/the-brazilian-way-of-lawfare-gets-bolsonaro-cefd48ba">Opinion | The Brazilian Way of Lawfare Gets Bolsonaro</a> &mdash; The Wall Street Journal</h3>
      <p>A biased Supreme Court convicts the former president and gives him 27 years.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/colombia-coca-growing-region-transition-peace-is-stumbling-2025-09-11/">In Colombia coca-growing region, transition to peace is stumbling</a> &mdash; Reuters</h3>
      <p>In Colombia coca-growing region, transition to peace is stumbling</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2025/09/12/colombia-cartels-united-states-support-war/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=wp_homepage">America cannot afford to abandon Colombia’s drug fight</a> &mdash; The Washington Post</h3>
      <p>U.S.-Colombia cooperation is crucial in the war on cartels and cocaine trafficking.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.wsj.com/world/americas/argentine-president-milei-calls-his-sister-the-boss-now-shes-a-liability-accd2ff2">Argentine President Milei Calls His Sister ‘the Boss.’ Now She’s a Liability.</a> &mdash; The Wall Street Journal</h3>
      <p>An election loss and bribery allegations have put a spotlight on Karina Milei and her influence on her older brother.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.ft.com/content/9c0c5a18-2f4e-4b91-a585-cac95a34c2e4">Javier Milei stumbles into crisis ahead of Argentina’s crucial midterms</a> &mdash; The Financial Times</h3>
      <p>Libertarian president gets ‘wake-up call’ after disappointing local elections</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/sep/14/mexico-sugary-drinks-tax-obesity">Attack on obesity or cash grab? Tax hike on sugary drinks divides opinion in Mexico</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>Mexicans, who consume on average 166 litres of fizzy drinks a year, will face a near doubling of the tax rate
Coca-Cola country in southern Mexico – photo essay

Mexico has declared war on one of its deadliest foes – but not one of the country’s many powerful drug cartels. Rather, the Latin American country has doubled down on its battle against a more silent killer: sugary drinks.
“We want people to stop drinking so much soft drink,” said President Claudia Sheinbaum bluntly at a news conference this week. The country’s 2026 budget, unveiled on Monday, proposed to nearly double the current tax rate on sugary drinks from 1.64 pesos (9 cents) per liter to 3.08 pesos per liter.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    ]]></description>
    </item>
</channel>
    </rss>