<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <rss version="2.0">
      <channel>
        <title>LatAm Prompt News Digest</title>
        <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
        <description>A daily digest of curated Latin American news.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 07:19:17 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <managingEditor>LatAm Prompt News Feed</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>LatAm Prompt News Feed</webMaster>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      
    <item>
      <title>LatAm Prompt News Digest - August 18, 2025</title>
      <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-08-18</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 07:19:17 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>LatAm Prompt News Feed</author>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <h3><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivwFBVV95cUxNMDFOdDdhbEdFc2JQRlpSaElLQUJ0Yk5HTjl4YjFUVnhkWldrNVR3aHFFZ2gyeEZHQU9oNDM4djNfdVFKdjFybFR1LWlOSFVmWGNzU0I5YUxMeEtEeXlMdXFMN0tVTkE1TDBLWHFRdmFqdW9qMVp0ckp1UUFqdGYyMFNleXoxdmdaN29hd1Q0LTF6RlVIYlBQelFZOUR5V0RBbG5Zbl92V2Y3QlpuaVlaSFlMMENFeHl6UjZIX1ZjOA?oc=5">How Bolivia’s Economic Crisis Is Shaping the Election</a> &mdash; </h3>
      <p>How Bolivia’s Economic Crisis Is Shaping the Election</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxQaEs5eEJVdXREYWpFaWtKRnlpLTI0dGtyTmtBVDg0MFVWemRLZURTTmdLaFRwbXZhZmRqQ2VzNDllQ1otOXE5V2NYZVRRSkVQWFIxYjhJYzFJd1dub1kzSWJfVzNidEM5SXp3NzR4a05yR3RHZHk4bHNhcU1RVHcxRjRIQkpkd2VLUzBrdm9RQzdOYTZtWjJLby1USlFLZ2xJY0hSMUYyN0w1anB6eUJiZUYxUVFQcXJYUm5tSUlB?oc=5">Colombia’s Opposition Is Hobbled by Senator’s Murder, Leader’s Scandal</a> &mdash; </h3>
      <p>Colombia’s Opposition Is Hobbled by Senator’s Murder, Leader’s Scandal</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2025/08/16/evo-morales-bolivia-election/">A Latin American experiment in socialism could be nearing its end</a> &mdash; </h3>
      <p>Evo Morales was credited with lifting millions out of poverty and nurturing a growing middle class. But now Bolivia appears to be shifting rightward.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/08/16/us/haiti-gang-barbeque-bounty.html">Why Is the U.S. Offering a $5 Million Reward for a Haitian Gang Leader?</a> &mdash; </h3>
      <p>A major bounty has been offered for help apprehending Jimmy Cherizier, a gang leader known as “Barbecue.” Experts have doubts about whether it will make any difference.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c93k3l373n5o">Once a place of horror, now a tourist town - with an uncertain future</a> &mdash; </h3>
      <p>Chile wants to turn the site where a cult leader tortured prisoners and abused his followers into a memorial.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/aug/17/bolivians-go-to-polls-in-election-that-could-end-20-years-of-socialism">Bolivians go to polls in election that could end 20 years of socialism</a> &mdash; </h3>
      <p>Rightwing candidates lead polling ahead of fragmented left amid country’s worst economic crisis in four decades
Bolivians are going to the polls in an election that could mark a shift to the right – and the end of nearly 20 years of rule by the leftist Movimiento al Socialismo (Mas).
The party, which came to power with the first election of Evo Morales in 2005, risks losing its legal status if it fails to reach 3% – a threshold it has not hit in polls.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/08/17/world/americas/bolivia-presidential-election-explained.html">What to Know About Bolivia’s Presidential Election</a> &mdash; </h3>
      <p>An economic crisis and political infighting among the country’s long-dominant socialist party could pave the way for the first right-wing president in decades.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.wsj.com/opinion/dont-bomb-mexico-mr-president-75bcc45f">Opinion | Don’t Bomb Mexico, Mr. President</a> &mdash; </h3>
      <p>There are better ways of fighting the drug cartels—and Claudia Sheinbaum will help.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxPank4UE1HdVZnNnVPYWNicTZ5VUx6aDZJLUZBRmxHcGtRRnY4Z2dURXk2cnFwZzUtM2dEa1hHZl83WjNXT20ydW1ZaGxzU1RURkhwb1RDZXZLZDhhNjVDZ3lIUkN2XzVvVzVzM3JlanBFamtCbkloYnpXcGpWemhiNmUtejRGVXViV2ttYlFsRXkxanF5Z3FWank3NzQ2OEo4U2FQRmtaZF95MXNQdG9KUy16NkM?oc=5">Two Decades of Socialist Rule May End as Bolivians Start Voting</a> &mdash; </h3>
      <p>Two Decades of Socialist Rule May End as Bolivians Start Voting</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/aug/18/bolivia-presidential-election-preliminary-results">Bolivia presidential election: preliminary results put two rightwing candidates in run-off vote</a> &mdash; </h3>
      <p>First-round result marks the end of nearly 20 years of dominance by the leftist Movimiento al Socialismo as economic crisis grips the country
Bolivia’s presidential election will go to a run-off for the first time, with two rightwing candidates competing for the presidency – marking the end of nearly 20 years of dominance by the leftist Movimiento al Socialismo (Mas).
The candidate with the most votes, however, turned out to be a surprise: centre-right senator Rodrigo Paz Pereira, 57, who had started the campaign with just 3% support in opinion polls.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c4gzlp85432o">Bolivia set to elect first non-left wing president in two decades</a> &mdash; </h3>
      <p>The rightward turn by the Bolivian electorate can see changes in economic policies and closer US ties.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.wsj.com/world/americas/bolivians-vote-out-socialists-after-two-decades-in-power-02d0a56f">Bolivians Vote Out Socialists After Two Decades in Power</a> &mdash; </h3>
      <p>Voters angered by soaring inflation and fuel shortages back market-friendly candidates to overhaul Bolivia’s economy.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.ft.com/content/d2138a80-8916-42c8-ae95-f5c239367672">Trump pressure lights fire under Mexico’s ‘powder keg’ ruling party</a> &mdash; </h3>
      <p>President Sheinbaum grapples with power vacuum left by her mentor and predecessor López Obrador</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.ft.com/content/dccf800f-21ca-4c99-af96-a16f1c2fac25">Bolivia heads to presidential run-off after ruling leftwing party collapses</a> &mdash; </h3>
      <p>Country set to swing to right as soaring inflation contributes to first loss for MAS in 20 years</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2025/08/18/brazil-moraes-judge-trump-bolsonaro/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=wp_homepage">The judge who refuses to bend to Trump’s will: ‘We’ll do what’s right’</a> &mdash; </h3>
      <p>Alexandre de Moraes says he’s preserving Brazilian democracy. The White House says he’s destroying it.</p>
      <hr/>
    ]]></description>
    </item>
</channel>
    </rss>