<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <rss version="2.0">
      <channel>
        <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed</title>
        <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
        <description>A daily digest of curated Latin American news.</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 08:02:23 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <managingEditor>LatAm Prompt News Feed</managingEditor>
        <webMaster>LatAm Prompt News Feed</webMaster>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
      
    <item>
      <title>LatAm Prompt News Feed - September 03, 2025</title>
      <link>https://latamprompt.github.io/Online-Feed/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-09-03</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 08:02:23 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>LatAm Prompt News Feed</author>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2025/sep/03/lithium-mining-bolivia-salt-flats-indigenous-environment-ecosystem">‘The Dubai of South America’: how the promise of riches from lithium mining turned to dust in Bolivia</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>Politicians have long promised the critical metal will rescue the economy but Indigenous locals say the push to exploit vast reserves threatens the ecosystem and their livelihoods
• Photographs by Sara Aliaga Ticona
Growing up near Bolivia’s Uyuni salt flats, Franz Alí Ramos remembers playing in the high-altitude wetlands near his home during the rainy season. “It was a beautiful recreation area for us and for animals,” he says.
Now, the wetlands have given way to cracked, sunbaked earth – a change that Alí Ramos blames on nearby operations by Bolivia’s state lithium corporation, Yacimientos de Litio Bolivianos (YLB). The government has recently signed lithium mining contracts with two foreign companies – one Russian and the other Chinese – and residents fear more serious damage is yet to come.
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/sep/03/amazon-love-motels-cop30-summit">Brazil’s Amazon love motels ditch erotic decor to host Cop30 climate summit</a> &mdash; The Guardian</h3>
      <p>In Belém, motels known for sex chairs and mirrored ceilings are stripping risqué features for climate negotiators
Guests at the Love Lomas Pousada in the Amazon city of Belém receive an email from reception before check-in with two questions, one conventional, the other ​unforeseen.
“Could you kindly let us know what time you expect to arrive at our establishment,” the message reads. “And one other thing, our rooms feature erotic chairs. Would you like to have it removed?”
 Continue reading...</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/podcasts/post-reports/they-were-deported-to-el-salvadors-megaprison-what-happened-inside/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=wp_homepage">They were deported to El Salvador's megaprison. What happened inside?</a> &mdash; The Washington Post</h3>
      <p>The story of Roger Molina, a Venezuelan migrant who was sent by the Trump administration to El Salvador’s megaprison.</p>
      <hr/>
    
      <h3><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2025-09-02/the-us-navy-just-sent-a-clear-message-to-maduro-and-venezuela">The US Military Just Sent a Clear Message to Maduro and Venezuela</a> &mdash; Bloomberg</h3>
      <p>The US Military Just Sent a Clear Message to Maduro and Venezuela</p>
      <hr/>
    ]]></description>
    </item>
</channel>
    </rss>